linfield.edu 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy - Linfield College

The website domain, linfield.edu, is owned by and is the responsibility of Linfield College. The following policies apply to linfield.edu and all other websites/pages owned and operated by Linfield College.

**Personal Information**  
Linfield collects and stores personal information that is voluntarily provided to us through web forms, mailings, and phone solicitation.

Linfield also collects some non-personally identifiable information from individuals visiting our website.  This may include the visitor’s IP address, date and time of the website visit and  pages(s) visited. Linfield may also collect information that it receives from your web browser, including device type (desktop, tablet, smart phone), browser type and version, and operating system.  This information helps us understand how visitors use our site so we can improve user experiences.

Linfield College understands and respects the importance of maintaining the privacy and security of your personal information. If you supply us with your mailing address, telephone numbers, or email address, you may receive telephone or email messages from us about our degrees and certificates, programs and services, or upcoming events.

Linfield College will not sell, rent, or trade your personal information to any third party. Information may be collected and shared with third parties such as secure merchant banks for admission application deposits, online admission applications, billing, address updates, ordering textbooks, event registration, online gifts to the college, and for other uses relevant to the College.

****Cookies**  
**Cookies are small text files delivered by our site and stored by your web browser. Cookies do not store personal information. They track data such as computer IP address, pages browsed, date and time of visit, browser type, computer operating system, and links used to enter or leave our website.  You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it, or refuse cookies altogether.

**Google Analytics**  
Linfield College uses Google Analytics to analyze how our visitors use our website. This includes paths a user follows to arrive at a page, the amount of time a user spent on a page, and what page a user was on when they exited our site. Google Analytics does not collect information that personally identifies individual users, such as names, social security numbers, phone numbers or email addresses. This information may be used by the college or third parties such as Google to track and understand visitor interactions within the linfield.edu site. This will help us provide a better user experience by better targeting user needs.

To opt out of user data collection on Linfield's website, Google recommends installing the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

**Online Advertising**  
Linfield College uses Google Analytics Advertising Features that allows for certain forms of display advertising and other advanced features. Subject to change, the Google Display Advertising features Linfield College currently uses are Display and Search Remarketing, Audience Demographics and Interests Reporting and DoubleClick Campaign Manager reporting.

These features are used to deliver Linfield advertisements online and to allow third-party vendors, including Google, to show Linfield College advertising online. These features also allow Linfield College and third-party vendors, including Google, to use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on users past visits to the website and to report how ad impressions, uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to the website. Data from Google's interest-based advertising or third-party audience data may also be combined with Google Analytics to better understand the needs of users of this website and to improve our services.

You may opt out of display advertising by visiting your [Google Ads Settings page,](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)  [modifying your ad settings on your personal device](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662856?hl=en-AU), or by installing and running the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

**Links to Other Websites**  
Linfield College’s website contains links to other websites that have no affiliation with Linfield. Linfield also outsources some parts of its web presence to onside vendors, such as our [varsity athletics site](https://golinfieldwildcats.com/). Linfield is not responsible for the privacy policies of these other sites. Please review the privacy policies of those sites by visiting their policy links.
